<configuration>

  <!-- Query and DDL Execution -->
  <property>
    <name>hive.execution.engine</name>
    <value>tez</value>
    <description>Chooses execution engine. Options are: mr (Map Reduce, default), tez (Tez execution, for Hadoop 2 only), or spark (Spark execution, for Hive 1.1.0 onward).

    While mr remains the default engine for historical reasons, it is itself a historical engine and is deprecated in the Hive 2 line (HIVE-12300). It may be removed without further warning.

    See Hive on Tez and Hive on Spark for more information, and see the Tez section and the Spark section below for their configuration properties. Default: mr</description>
  </property>

  <!-- Scratch directory -->
  <property>
    <name>hive.exec.scratchdir</name>
    <value>hdfs://master:9000/home/hive/scratch</value>
    <description>HDFS root scratch directory for Hive jobs, which gets created with write all (733) permission. For each connecting user, an HDFS scratch directory ${hive.exec.scratchdir}/${username} is created with ${hive.scratch.dir.permission}. This directory is used by Hive to store the plans for different map/reduce stages for the query as well as to stored the intermediate outputs of these stages. Default: /tmp/hive</description>
  </property>
  
  <property>
    <name>hive.tez.container.size</name>
    <value>2048</value>
    <description>If this is not specified, the memory settings from the MapReduce configurations (mapreduce.map.memory.mb) are used by default for map tasks. Default: -1</description>
  </property>
  
  <property>
    <name>hive.tez.java.opts</name>
    <value>-XX:+UseG1GC</value>
    <description>If this is not specified, the MapReduce java opts settings (mapreduce.map.java.opts) are used by default. Default: (empty)</description>
  </property>
  
  <property>
    <name>hive.jar.directory</name>
    <value>hdfs://master:9000/home/hive/lib</value>
    <description>This is the location that Hive in Tez mode will look for to find a site-wide installed Hive instance. See hive.user.install.directory for the default behavior. Default: (empty)</description>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>hive.user.install.directory</name>
    <value>hdfs://master:9000/home/hive/install</value>
    <description>If Hive (in Tez mode only) cannot find a usable Hive jar in hive.jar.directory, it will upload the Hive jar to ${hive.user.install.directory}/${user_name} and use it to run queries. Default: hdfs:///user/</description>
  </property>

</configuration>