<configuration>

  <property>
    <name>tez.lib.uris</name>
    <value>hdfs://master:9000/home/yarn/tez/tez-0.9.2.tar.gz</value>
    <description>String value to a file path. The location of the Tez libraries which will be localized for DAGs. This follows the following semantics

    1. To use a single .tar.gz or .tgz file (generated by the tez build), the full path to this file (including filename) should be specified. The internal structure of the uncompressed tgz will be retained under $CWD/tezlib.
    2. If a single file is specified without the above mentioned extensions - it will be treated as a regular file. This means it will not be uncompressed during runtime.
    3. If multiple entries exist
        - Files: will be treated as regular files (not uncompressed during runtime)
        - Directories: all files under the directory (non-recursive) will be made available (but not uncompressed during runtime).
        - All files / contents of directories are flattened into a single directory - $CWD
    Default: null</description>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.use.cluster.hadoop-libs</name>
    <value>false</value>
    <description>Boolean value. Specify whether hadoop libraries required to run Tez should be the ones deployed on the cluster. This is disabled by default - with the expectation being that tez.lib.uris has a complete tez-deployment which contains the hadoop libraries. Default: false</description>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.am.shuffle.auxiliary-service.id</name>
    <value>tez_shuffle</value>
    <description>A Tez specific shuffle handler allows Tez DAGs to shuffle data in a way that takes advantage of the new features in Tez. In particular, the Tez shuffle handler allows DAGs to shuffle data more efficiently for Tez’s new data movements types and runtime optimizations, such as auto-reduce parallelism. Long running Tez sessions will be able to clean up intermediate data for completed queries and Tez applications can decide to clean up completed intermediate data for running applications.</description>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.am.launch.cluster-default.cmd-opts</name>
    <value>-XX:+UseG1GC -XX:+ResizeTLAB -XX:+UseNUMA -XX:-ResizePLAB</value>
    <description>String value. Command line options which will be prepended to {@link #TEZ_AM_LAUNCH_CMD_OPTS} during the launch of the AppMaster process. This property will typically be configured to include default options meant to be used by all jobs in a cluster. If required, the values can be overridden per job. Default: -server -Djava.net.preferIPv4Stack=true -Dhadoop.metrics.log.level=WARN</description>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.am.launch.cmd-opts</name>
    <value></value>
    <description>String value. Command line options provided during the launch of the Tez AppMaster process. Its recommended to not set any Xmx or Xms in these launch opts so that Tez can determine them automatically. Default: -XX:+PrintGCDetails -verbose:gc -XX:+PrintGCTimeStamps -XX:+UseNUMA -XX:+UseParallelGC</description>
  </property>

  <!-- LLAP -->
  <property>
    <name>tez.am.resource.memory.mb</name>
    <value>2048</value>
    <description>Int value. The amount of memory in MB to be used by the AppMaster. It shoud be set to the value of yarn.scheduler.minimum-allocation-mb. Default: 1024</description>
  </property>

  <!-- Tez UI
  <property>
    <name>tez.history.logging.service.class</name>
    <value>org.apache.tez.dag.history.logging.ats.ATSHistoryLoggingService</value>
    <description>String value that is a class name. Specify the class to use for logging history data. Default: org.apache.tez.dag.history.logging.impl.SimpleHistoryLoggingService</description>
  </property>

  <property>
    <name>tez.tez-ui.history-url.base</name>
    <value>http://master:9999/tez-ui/</value>
    <description>String value Tez-UI Url base. This gets replaced in the TEZ_AM_TEZ_UI_HISTORY_URL_TEMPLATE ex http://ui-host:9001 or if its hosted with a prefix http://ui-host:9001/~user if the ui is hosted on the default port (80 for http and 443 for https), the port should not be specified. Default: null</description>
  </property>
  -->

</configuration>
